I don't know your name. Audience Member: Howard. Howard.
لا أعرف اسمك. ( أحد الحضور: هورد . هورد.)
Thom Mayne: Howard? I'm sitting next to Howard. I don't know Howard, obviously,
هورد ؟ لقد كنت جالسا بجوار هورد. من الواضح أني لا أعرف هوارد.
and he's going, I hope you're not next.
ثم قال ، ارجو ان لا تكون التالي .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Amazing. Amazing performance.
رائع. أداء رائع
I kind of erased everything in my brain to follow that.
لقد محوت كل ما في عقلي علي نحو ما ، كي أستطيع أجري ذلك.
Let me start some place. I'm interested --
و،لكن ... دعوني ابدأ من مكان ما ... أنا مهتم ..
I kind of do the same thing, but I don't move my body. (Laughter)
يبدو أني أفعل نفس الشيء، لكني لا أحرك جسدي.
And instead of using human figures to develop ideas of time and space,
و بدلا عن استيحاء أفكارنا عن الزمن والحيز أعضاء جسد الإنسان،
I work in the mineral world. I work with more or less inert matter.
أنا اعمل في العالم المادي، اعمل مع مواد أقل أو أكثر خمولا.
And I organize it. And, well, it's also a bit different
وانظمها، حسنا...لكن الامر مختلفا قليلا
because an architect versus, let's say, a dance company
لان المعماري مقارنة برفيق الرقص إن جاز لنا التعبير
finally is a negotiation between one's private world,
هو تفاوض بين عالم المرء الخاص
one's conceptual world, the world of ideas, the world of aspirations,
عالمه الافتراضي، عالم من الافكار, عالم ملئه الطموحات.
of inventions, with the relationship of the exterior world
و الاختراعات، مع علاقة المرء بالعالم الخارجي.
and all the limitations, the naysayers.
بكل العقبات والمخذلين .
Because I have to say, for my whole career,
لانه يتوجب علي ان أقول علي طول مجري حياتي المهنية
if there's anything that's been consistent, it's been that you can't do it.
إذا كان هناك شيء ظل علي حاله، لطالما كان الشيء الذي تعسر عليك فعله.
No matter what I've done, what I've tried to do,
أيا كان ما فعلت لإنجازه، أيا كان محاولاتك.
everybody says it can't be done.
كل أحد لا يستطيع إنجاز عمله.
And it's continuous across the complete spectrum of the various
وهو يبقي كذلك باستمرار في طيف واسع
kind of realities that you confront with your ideas.
من كافة أنواع مسلمات الواقع التي تجابه أفكارك
And to be an architect, somehow you have to negotiate between left and right,
و ان تكون معماريا، يتوجب عليك ان تداول بين اليمين والشمال
and you have to negotiate between this very private place where ideas take place
كما يجب عليك ان تداول بين هذا المكان ألموغل في الخصوصية حيث تولد الافكار
and the outside world, and then make it understood.
و العالم الخارجي ، ثم تجعله قابلا للفهم
I can start any number of places, because this process is also --
أستطيع أني ابدأ أي عدد من الأمكنه، لان هذه العمليه أيضا ..
I think -- very different from some of the morning sessions,
أظن .... أنها مختلفه جدا عن الجلسات الصباحية ...
which you had such a kind of very clear, such a lineal idea,
حيث تتملكك أفكار متسقة واضحة نوعا ما ...
like the last one, say, with Howard,
كتلك الاخيره، لنقل مع هوارد.
that I think the creative process in architecture,
و هذا ما أحسبه النهج الابداعي في العمارة.
the design process, is extremely circuitous. It's labyrinthine.
التفاعل التصميمي عملية معقدة و متاهية إلي حد لا متناهي
It's Calvino's idea of the quickest way between two points
أنها فكرة (كالفينو) ان اقرب مسافة بين نقطتين
is the circuitous line, not the straight line.
هي الخط المتعرج و ليس المستقيم
And definitely my life has been part of that.
بالتاكيد إن حياتي كانت على هذا النسق
I'm going to start with some simple kind of
سابدا حديثي
notions of how we organize things.
بفكره بسيطة عن كيفية تنظيمنا للأشياء.
But basically, what we do is, we try to give coherence to the world.
لكن ما نفعله في الأساس، أن نحاول ان نعطي العالم ترابطا منطقيا
We make physical things, buildings
نصنع أشياء مادية ، المباني
that become a part in an accretional process; they make cities.
التي أصبحت جزء من عملية تلاحميه، صنعت مدننا
And those things are the reflection of the processes,
و ما هذه الاشياء إلا انعكس لهذه العملية
and the time that they are made.
والزمن الذي صنعت فيه
And what I'm doing is attempting to synthesize the way one sees the world
و ما أفعله أني أحاول ان أخلق طريقة يتمكن بها المرء من رؤية العالم
and the territories which are useful as generative material.
و الممتلكات التي يمكن ان تشكل مادة خلاقه
Because, really, all I'm interested in, always, as an architect,
لأنه ، في الحقيقة ، كل ما يهمني في كل الاحوال كمعماري
is the way things are produced because that's what I do. Right?
هو كيفية صناعة الاشياء لان هذه هي طبيعه عملي ، أليس كذلك ؟
And it's not based on an a priori notion.
و هي ليست مبنية علي فكره مسبقة
I have no interest at all in conceiving something in my brain
لست مهتما علي الإطلاق بتصور شىء في ذهني
and saying, "This is what it looks like." In fact, somebody mentioned --
ثم أقول " هكذا تبدو". في الحقيقة، أحد ما ذكر
Ewan, maybe it was you in your introduction --
إيوان، لربما كانت في مقدمة كلامك.
about this is what architects --
عن ماهية المعماري
did somebody say it's what business people come to,
هل قال أحد ما أنها ما توصل إليه أصحاب العمل
it's what the corporate world comes to
أو أنها ما توصل اليه عالم الشركات الكبرى
when they want to make it look like something at the end of the line? Huh. Wow.
حينما يريدون ان يجعلوها تبدو في أوج الحداثة ؟ وااو
It doesn't work that way for me at all.
ليس الأمر كذلك بالنسبة لي تماما
I have no interest in that whatsoever.
لست مهتما بذلك باي طريقة كانت
Architecture is the beginning of something, because it's --
العمارة هي البداية لشيء ما، لانها
if you're not involved in first principles,
لو لم تكن معنيا بالمباديء الاولى
if you're not involved in the absolute,
لو لم تكن معنيا بالمطلق
the beginning of that generative process, it's cake decoration.
ألبداية لتلك العملية التخليقية ، تشبه تزيين ألكعكة
And I've nothing wrong with cake decoration and cake decorators,
و ليس عندي ما يعيب تزيين الكعك ولا مزينين الكعك
if anybody's involved in cake decorations --
إذا شارك أي أحد في تزيين كعكة
it's not what I'm interested in doing. (Laughter)
ليس هذا محل اهتمامي
And so, in the formation of things, in giving it form,
لذلك فان تشكيل الأشياء ، إعطائها شكلا، اعطائها
in concretizing these things,
في تجسيد تلكم الأشياء
it starts with some notion of how one organizes.
انها تبدأ بفكره طريقة ترتيب المرء للاشياء
And I've had for 30 years an interest in a series of complexities
لطالما اهتممت بسلسلة من التجميعات علي الثلاثين عاما الفائتة
where a series of forces are brought to bear,
حيث جيء بمجموعة من القوى لحملها
and to understand the nature of the final result of that,
ولكي أفهم طبيعة النتيجة النهاية لذلك
representing the building itself.
متمثلة في المبني بحد ذاته
There's been a continual relationship between inventions,
هنالك علاقه مستدامة بين الاختراعات
which are private, and reality, which has been important to me.
الخاصة في كنهها والواقع ، ما كان من الاهمية بمكان عندي
A project which is part of an exhibition in Copenhagen 10 years ago,
أحد مشاريعي كان جزء ا من معرض في كوبنهاجن قبل عشر سنوات
which was the modeling of a hippocampus --
و هو عباره عمل نموذج للهيببوكامبوس (الحصين)
the territory of the brain that records short-term memory --
-- المنطقة من الدماغ التي تحفظ الذاكرة قصيرة المدي--
and the documentation of that, the imaginative and documentation of that
و التوثيق لذلك، التوثيق التخيلي لذلك
through a series of drawings which literally attempt to organize that experience.
من خلال سلسلة من الرسومات . التي تعمل علي ان تنظم تلك التجربة
And it had to do with the notion of walking a kilometer,
كما ان لها بعلاقة بفكرة المشي لكيلومتر
observing every kilometer a particular object of desire,
ملاحظة كل كيلومتر يشكل جزء معين من الغاية.
and then placing that within this.
و من ثم وضع ذاك ضمنه
And the notion was that I could make an organization
و الفكره من وراء ذاك أني استطعت ان أكون منظمة
not built on normal coherencies, but built on non-sequiturs, built on randomness.
ليست مبنية على التسلسل المنطقي الطبيعي، بل مبنية على أساس اللا منطق ، مبنية على العشوائية
And I'd been extremely interested in this notion of randomness
لطالما كنت معنيا بشده بمفهوم العشوائية.
as it produces architectural work
وانتاجه للعمل المعماري
and as it definitely connects to the notion of the city,
ووصله بمفهوم المدينة
an accretional notion of the city,
المفهوم المتنامي للمدينة
and that led to various ideas of organization.
الذي أدي إلي أفكار متعددة عن المؤسسة
And then this led to broader ideas of buildings
الذي بدوره أدي أفكار أوسع عن المباني
that come together through the multiplicity of systems.
كل هذا تجمعه نظام تعددي
And it's not any single system that makes the work.
ليس هناك نظام ينجز العمل بمفرده
It's the relationship -- it's the dynamics between the systems --
أنها العلاقة بين الانظمه ، والدينامكية فيما بينها
which have the power to transform and invent
التي بدورها لها القوة لتحول وتخترع
and produce an architecture that is -- that would otherwise not exist.
وتنتج عماره ما كان لها ان تكون بخلاف ذلك
And those systems could be identified,
وهذه الانظمه يمكن تعريفها
and they could be grouped together.
ويمكن تقسيمها علي مجموعات
And of course, today, with the technology of the computer
وبالطبع اليوم وبفضل تقنية الحاسوب
and with the rapid prototyping, etc., we have the mechanisms
والنمذجة المرئية المتنامية و ما إلى ذلك . ما وفر لنا الالية
to understand and to respond to these systems,
للتجاوب و فهم هذه الانظمه
and to allow them to adjust to the various accommodations of functionalities
وإعطائها المجال لتتحور إلي وضعيات وظيفىة مختلفة
because that's all we do.
لان هذا ما نفعله
We're producing spaces that accommodate human activity.
نحن ننتج حيز توافق مع الانشطة الإنسانية
And what I'm interested in is not the styling of that,
و ما يهمني ليست الطريقة
but the relationship of that as it enhances that activity.
لكن العلاقة التي تعضد ذلك النشاط
And that directly connects to ideas of city-making.
وصلتها المباشرة بفكرة صنع المدينة
This is a project that we just finished in Penang
هذا مشروع أكملته لتوي في بينانج
for a very, very large city project that came directly out of this process,
لمشروع مدني كبير جدا كان نتاجا مباشرا لهذه العملية
which is the result of the multiplicity of forces that produce it.
الذي هو نتيجة للقوى المتعددة التي أنتجته
And the project -- again, enormous, enormous competition --
و المشروع---- مره أخرى--- كان منافسه هائلة
on the Hudson River and in New York
في نهر هدسن في نيويورك
that we were asked to do three years ago, which uses these processes.
طلب منا قبل ثلاث سنوات ان نقوم به ، الذي يستخدم هذا النهج
And what you're looking at are possibilities that have to do
و ما تنظرون إليه عبارة عن احتمالات يتوجب علينا فعلها
with the generation of the city as one applies a methodology
مع جيل من المدينة كواحد يطبق منهجية
that uses notions of these multiple forces,
تستخدم مفهوم القوي المتعددة
that deals with the enormity of the problem, the complexity of the problem,
التي بدورها تتفاعل مع شناعة المشكلة، تعقيد المشكلة
when we're designing cities at larger and larger aggregates.
حينما نصمم مدن على نطاق تجمعات أكبر واكبر
Because one of the issues today is
لان واحد من المشاكل اليوم
that the economic aggregate is driving the development aggregate,
ان التجمع الاقتصادي هو الذي يقود التجمع التنموي
and as the aggregates get larger we require
و مع توسع التجمعات نتطلب
more and more complex investigation processes to solve these problems.
المزيد والمزيد من التحرك الدقيق لحل هذه المشاكل
And that led us directly to the Olympic Village.
هذا يقودنا مباشر للقرية الاولمبية
I was in New York on Monday presenting it to the IOC.
كنت في نيويورك يوم الاثنين أقدم عرضا للجنة الأولمبية الدولية (IOC)
We won the competition -- what was it, nine months ago?
فزنا بالمناقصة ...التي كانت ، قبل تسعة أشهر
Again, a direct reflection from using these processes
مره أخرى ، انعكاس مباشر لاستخدام هذا النهج
to develop extremely complicated, very large-scale organisms.
لتطوير كيان كبير جدا ، غاية في التعقيد
And then, also, was working with broad strategies.
و من ثم أيضا يعمل باستراتيجيات ذات طيف واسع
In this case, we only used 15 of the 60 acres of land,
في هذه الحالة ، استعملنا فقط 15 من أصل 60 هكتار من الأرض .
and the 45 acres was a park and would become the legacy of the Olympic Village.
وال 45 هكتار المتبقية استعملت كمتنزه سيصبح ارثا للقرية الولمبية
And it would become the second largest park in the boroughs, etc.
وستصبح ثاني أكبر متنزه علي مستوى (بروغ)...وما إلى ذلك
Its position, of course, in the middle of Manhattan -- it's on Hunter's Point.
موقعه بالطبع ، في وسط منهاتن . موقع مميز جدا
And then the broader ideas of city-making
من ثم علي مستوى أعلى ، إن فكرة صنع المدينة
start having direct influences on architecture,
بدأت تؤثر تأثيرا مباشرا على العمارة ككل
on the elements that make up the broader scheme,
على العناصر المكونة لكل المخطط
the buildings themselves, and start guiding us.
على المباني نفسها ، وبدأت تقود اتجاهنا
Architecture for me has been an investigation of a multiplicity of forces
العمارة بالنسبة لي هي تحري للقوى المتعددة
that could come from literally any place.
التي باستطاعتها ان تأتي من أي مكان
And so I can start this discussion in any number of places,
لذا فأني أستطيع ان ابدأ هذا الحوار في أماكن متعددة
and I've chosen three or four to talk about.
و لقد اخترت ثلاث إلى أربع لتحدث عنها
And it has also to do with an interest in
و هي أيضا لها علاقة بالاهتمام
the vast kind of territory that architecture touches.
بالنطاق الشاسع بالمناطق التي تمسها العمارة
It literally is connected to anything in terms of knowledge base.
والتي بدورها توصل بأي شيء استنادا على الاساس المعرفي
There's just no place that it doesn't somehow
بطريقة ما ليس هناك مكان لا يملك
have a connective tissue to.
نسييج توصيلي لكي
This is Jim Dine, and it's the absence of presence, etc.
هذا جيم دين، و هذا غياب الحضور ...و ما إلى ذلك
It's the clothing, the skin, without the presence of the character.
هي الملبس، الجلد ، من غير وجود الشخصية
It became kind of an idea for the notion of the surface of a work,
تصبح نوعه ما فكره لمفهوم السطح لعمل ما
and it was used in a project where we could unravel that surface,
و لقد استخدمت في مشروع حيث استطعنا الكشف عن السطح
and it was a figurative idea that was going to be folded
و قد كانت فكره رمزية كانت في طريقها إلى أن تطوي
and made into a very, kind of complex space.
وتُشكل إلي حيز مركب لطيف
And the idea was the relationship of the space,
والفكرة كانت علاقة الحيز
which was made up of the fold of the image,
المصنوع من طي الصورة
and the dialectic or the conflict between the figuration,
و جدلية الصراع بين الرموز
and the clarity of the image
وإلي حد ما وضوح الصورة
and the complexity of the space, which were in dialog.
و تعقيد الحيز ، الذي كان في حوار
And it made us rethink the whole notion of how we work
يجلعنا نعيد التفكير في مفهوم طريقة عملنا ككل
and how we make things,
وكيفية عملنا للاشياء
and it led us to ideas that were closer to fashion design as we flattened out surfaces,
ما يقودنا لأفكار قريبة من تصميم الازياء بينما نسوي السطوح
and then brought them back together as they could make spatial combinations.
من ثم أعدت السطوح لكي يكونوا تواليف حيزية
And this was the first prototype in Korea,
و هذا كان النموذج الأول في كوريا
as we're dealing with a dynamic envelope,
بينما كنا نتعامل مع مظروف ديناميكي
and then the same characteristic of the fabric.
من ثم نفس صفات النسيج
It has a material identity and it's translucent and it's porous,
له هوية مادية، شفافة ومسامية
and it allows us for a very different notion of what a skin of a building is.
ما سمح لنا بطرق عديدة... نوع من مفهوم الجلد للمبني
And that turned right away into another project.
مما أخذنا الي مشروع اخر
This is the Caltrans building in Los Angeles.
هذا الكالترانس في لوس أنجلس
And now we're seeing as the skin and the body is differentiated.
والأن نري ما يشبه الجلد الجسم متمايزين
Again, it's a very, very simple notion.
مره أخرى أنه مفهوم مبسط للغاية
If you look at most buildings,
إذا نظرت إلى معظم المباني
what you look at is the building, the facade, and it is the building.
ما تنظر إليه هو المبنى ، الواجهة، وهو المبنى
And all of a sudden we're kind of moving away,
وفجاءة و بطريقة ما نبتعد تماما
and we're separating the skin from the body,
ونفصل الجلد من الجسم
and that's going to lead to broader performance criteria,
مما سيقود إلى معايير أوسع للاداء
which I'm going to talk about in a minute.
والتي ستحدث عنها بعد قليل
And you're looking at how it drapes over
أنتم تنظرون إلي كيفية ثني
and differentiates from the body.
وممايزة الجلد عن الجسم
And then, again, the building itself,
ثم مره أخرى المبني نفسه
middle of Los Angeles, right across from City Hall.
وسط لوس أنجلس . في الجهة المقابلة لمبني البلدية
And as it moves, it takes pieces of the earth with it. It bends up.
وبينما تتحرك تأخذ أجزاء من الرد معها .. و تنحني
It's part of a sign system,
انها جزء من نظام اشاره نوعا ما
which was part of the kind of legacy of Los Angeles --
التي كانت جزء من تراث لوس أنجلس
the two-dimension, three-dimension signing, etc.
ثنائي الأبعاد، تأشير ثلاثي الابعاد و هلمجرا
And then it allows one to penetrate the work itself.
و من ثم تسمح للمرء باختراق العمل نفسه
It's transparent, and it allows you to understand, I think,
فهي شفافة وتسمح لك بان تفهم . على ما أظن
what is always the most interesting thing in any building,
الذي دائما ما يكون أكثر شيء مثير للانتباه في أي مبني
which is the actual constructional processes that make it.
عملية التشييد هى المسئولة عن إبرازه
And it's probably the most intense kind of territory
و هي إلي حد ما المنطقة الأكثر أهمية
of the work, which is not occupied,
في العمل لكنها غير مستوعبة
because architecture is always the most interesting in some mechanism
لان العمارة دائما ما تكون الأكثر إثارة للاهتمام في بعض الاليات
when it's separated from function,
حينما تفصل من الوظيفة
and this is an area that allows for that.
و هنا مساحه قد تسمح بذلك
And then the skin starts transforming into other materials.
و من ثم الجلد يبدأ التحول إلي مواد أخرى
We're using light as a building material in this case.
و في هذه الحاله تم استخدام الضوء كمادة بناء
We're working with Keith Sonnier in New York,
نحن نعمل مع كيث سنر في نيويورك
and we're making this large outside room,
بينما كنا نعمل في تشييد غرفة خارجية كبيرة
which is possible in Los Angeles, and which is very much reflective
وهو امر ممكن في لوس انجليس، و إلى حد بعيد تعكس
of the urban, the contemporary urban environments
البعض المدني والبيئه المدنية الحديثة
that you would find in Shibuya or you'd find in Mexico City
التي تجدها في شيبوية كما يمكنك ان تجدها في مكسكو سيتي
or Sao Paulo, etc.,
أو في ساو باولو و هلمجرا
that have to do with activating the city over a longer span of time.
و لهذا علاقة بتفعيل المدينة علي المدي الطويل
And that was very much part of the notion
و هذا إلى حد بعيد مرتبط بمفهوم
of the urban objective of this project in Los Angeles.
الهدف المدني لهذا المشروع في لوس أنجلس
And, again, all of it promoting transparency.
و يعمل ككل علي تعزيز الشفافية
And an image which may be closest talks about the use of light as a medium,
و هذه الصورة أقرب ما تكون تعبر عن استخدام الضوء كوسيط
that light becomes literally a building material.
حيث يصبح الضوء أحد مواد البناء
Well, that immediately turned into something much broader, and as a scope.
حسنا، هذا يأخذنا مباشرة إلي امر أوسع.
And again, we're looking at an early sketch
هنا نحن ننظر إلى مخطط أولي
where I'm understanding now
حيث ما أفهمه الأن
that the skin can be a transition between the ground and the tower.
ان الجلد يمكن ان يكون منطقة انتقالية من الأرض الي البرج
This is a building in San Francisco which is under construction.
هذا مبني في سن فرانسيسكو ما زال تحت التشييد
And now it turned into something much, much broader as a problem,
والان تحول الي ان يكون مشكله على نطاق واسع
and it has to do with performance.
فيما يتعلق بالأداء
This will be the first building in the United States that took --
هذا سيكون أول مبني في الولايات المتحدة أخذ..
well, I can't say it took the air conditioning out. It's a hybrid.
حسنا، لا أستطيع ان أقول أنه أخرج نظام تكىيف الهواء للخارج ، إنه هجين
I wanted a pure thing, and I can't get it.
أردت شيئا أكثر نقاء ، لم أستطيع إيجاده
It's a wrong attitude, actually, because the hybrid is probably more interesting.
إنه سلوك خاطيء ، لان الهجين من المحتمل ان يكون أكثر جذبا للانتباه
But we took the air conditioning out of the tower.
لكننا أخرجنا تكيف ألهواء خارج البرج
There's some air conditioning left in the base,
هناك جزء من نظام التكيف ترك في القاعدة
but the skin now moves on hydraulics.
لكننا نمضي باتجاه تهجين الجلد
It forces air through a Venturi force if there's no wind.
حيث أنه يدخل الهواء عبر بالضخ إن لم تتوفر الرياح
It adjusts continually. And we removed the air conditioning.
حيث تعدل تلقائيا باستمرار ، وبذلك تخلصنا من نظام التكييف
Huge, huge thing. Half a million dollars a year delta.
أنه لأمر ضخم جدا فرق نصف مليون دولار سنويا
10 of these -- it's just under a million square feet --
10 منها تحتل فقط مليون قدم مربع
800 and some thousand square feet --
نحو ثمانمائة ألف قدم مربع
10 of these would power Sausalito -- the delta on this.
10 من هذه قادرة علي تزويد سوساليتو بالطاقة
And so now what we're looking at, as the projects get larger in scale,
ما تنظرون اليه هو مشروع ىكبر في المقياس
as they interface with broader problems,
كلما وجه بمشأكل أوسع
that they expand the capabilities
حيث يتسع أوجه مقدراته
in terms of their performance.
من حيث الأداء
Well, I could also start here.
حسنا، يمكنني أيضا البدء من هنا
We could talk about the relationship
يكن التحدث عن العلاقة
at a more biological sense of the relationship of building and ground.
من نطره حيوية لعلاقة المبني والأرض
Well, our research -- my generation for sure,
حسنا ، إن بحوثنا ...جيلى بلطبع
people who were going to school in the late '60s --
الجيل الذي ارتد الجامعه في أواخر الستينات
made very much a shift out of the internal focus of architecture,
أحدث طفرة هائلة في التركيز الداخلي للعمارة
looking at architecture within its own territory,
نظرا للعمارة من عمقها الخاص
and we were much more affected by film,
وكنا متاثرين إلى حد بعيد بالافلام
by what was going on in the art world, etc.
و مكان يدور في العالم و ما إلى ذلك
This is, of course, Michael Heizer.
هذا بالطبع مايكل هزار
And when I saw this, first an image and then visited,
لما رأيته كصورة أولا ثم قمت بزيارته
it completely changed the way I thought after that point.
غيرت طريقة تفكيري كليا
And I understood that building really could be
وفهمت ان المبني من الممكن أن يكون
the augmentation of the Earth's surface,
ما هو إلى الامتداد الطبيعي لسطح الأرض
and it completely shifted the notion of building ground in the most basic sense.
و بصورة كبيرة عضدت مفهوم أرضية البناء المتأصلة لدي
And then -- well, he was probably looking at this -- this is Nazca;
من ثم ، حسنا من الممكن ان يكون قد نظر إلى هذا ...هذه نزكا
this is 700 years ago -- the most amazing four-kilometer land sculptures.
هذا كان من سبعمائة عام --- من الأشياء المدهشه ....عمل النحت الممتد لاربعة كيلومترات
They're just totally incredible.
إنه لا يصدق
And that led us to then completely rethinking how we draw, how we work.
ما قادنا إلي اعادة التفكير في كيفيه الرسم و طريقة العمل
This is the first sketch of a high school in Pomona --
هذا مخطط أولي لمدرسة ثانوية في بومنا
well, whatever it is, a model, a conceptual, kind of idea.
حسنا أيا كان ذلك ... أنه مجسم ، عمل تخيلي لفكرة المشروع
And it's the reshaping of the Earth to make it occupiable.
و هذه اعاده تهييئه للأرض لتصبح قأبله لأن تعمّر من قبل البشر
So it puts 200,000 square feet of stuff that make a high school work
فهي بذلك تجمع 200000 قدم مربع من الاشياء التي تشكل مدرسة ثانوية
in the surface of that Earth.
في سطح تلك القطعه من الأرض
There it is modeled as it was developing into a piece of work.
و هنا تم تجسيمها لتصبح نوعا ما تطور لفكرة الي عمل
And there it is, again, as it's starting to get resolved tectonically,
ثم انتهي بها الأمر الي هذا، مره أخرى ، بدأت تطور معماريا
and then there's the school.
و من ثم هاهي مدرسة مكتملة
And, of course,
وبالطبع . إن مثار اهتمامنا
we're interested in participating with education.
نحن مهتمون بالمشاركة في العملية التعليمية
I have absolutely no interest in producing a building
لست مهتمة إطلاقا بإنتاج مبني
that just accommodates X, Y and Z function.
فقط لكي يسغل حيز ثلاثي الأبعد
What I'm interested in are how these ideas
مثار اهتمامي هو كيف لهذه الافكار
participate in the educational process of young people.
أن تشارك في العمليه التعليمية للجيل الناشيء
It demands some sort of notion of inquiry
انها تتطلب نوعه ما مفهوم التقصي
because it's a system that's developed not sculpturally.
لانه نظام لا يمكن التوصل إليه بالنحت
It's an idea that started from my first discussion.
إنها فكره تم استيحائها من أول حديثي
It has to do with a broad, consistent logic,
تتعلق بمنطق أوسع ومتسق
and that logic could be understood as one occupies the building.
و هذا المنطق يمكن للمرء ان يفهمه بمجرد ان يشغل المبني
And there's an overt -- at least,
و هنلك على الاقل صراحه
there's an attempt to make a very overt notion of a building
محاولة لابداء مفهوم بين عن المبني
that connects to the land in a very different way
يصله بالأرض بطرق مختلفة
because I was interested in a very didactic approach to the problem,
و لان محل اهتمامي ذو منحي تعليمي للتعامل مع المشكله
as one would understand that.
كيما يتسنى للمرء فهم ذلك
And the second project that was just finished in Los Angeles
و المشروع الثاني اكتمل لتوه في لوس انجليس
that uses some of the same ideas. It uses landscape as a major idea.
و الذي تم فيه استخدام بعد من هذه الأفكار ، تم استخدام البستنة كفكرة رئيسية
Then, again, we're doing the headquarters for NOAA --
ثم مره أخرى ، نحن نعمل مبني الرئاسة ل NOAA
National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Agency --
الوكالة القوميه لجغرافية المحيطات والغلاف الجوي
outside of Washington in Maryland.
خارج واشنجتون في ماريلاند
And this is how they see the world.
و هكذا ينظرون للعالم
They have 22 satellites zipping around at plus or minus 100 miles,
لديهم 22 قمر صناعي يدورون حول الأرض بمدارت تتراوح المائة ميل
and the site's in red.
الموقع باللون الأحمر
And what we really want to do -- well, the architects,
و ما نريد فعله ...حسنا المعماري
if there are architects out there, this is the Laugier Hut;
لو ان هناك معماريين ...هذا كوخ لاوقر
this is the primitive hut that's been around for so long --
هذا هو الكوخ التقليدي الذي استخدم لمده طويله
and what we wanted to do is really build this,
و أردنا فعله حقا هو بناء هذا
because they see themselves as the caretakers of the world,
لانهم يرون أنفسهم الرعاة الحقيقيون للعالم
and we wanted them to look down at their satellite,
و نحن نريدهم ان ينظروا لاقمارهم
how they see their own site, that eight-acre site,
الطريقة التي ينظرون بها لموقعهم ...تلك لثمانية هكتارات
and we wanted nothing left. We wanted it to stay green.
لا نريد أي شيء خلفنا ... أردنا له ان يبقي أخضرا
There's actually three baseball fields on it right now,
في الحقيقة ان به ثلاثه ملاعب بيسبول في الوقت الحالي
and they're going to stay there.
و سيبقوا هنالك
We put one piece directly north-south,
لقد وضعنا قطعه واحده مباشرة في الشمال الشرقي
and it holds the dishes at the ears, right?
و هو يحمل الصحون على الأذان، أليس كذلك
And then right below that the processing, and the mission lift,
و تحت ذلك مباشرة التجهيز ، ومصعد المهمة
and the mission control room, and all the other spaces are underground.
ثم غرفة المراقبة ، و كل بقيه الحوائز فهي تحت الأرض
And what you look at is an aircraft carrier
أما ما تنظرون إليه حامله طائرات
that's performance-driven by the cone vision of these satellite dishes.
مستوحاه من الشكل المخروطي لهذه الاطباق
And that the building itself is occupied in the lower portion,
مما يشكل أقل نسبة استيعاب للمبني في حد ذاته
broken up by a series of courts,
منفصلة بعدد من الفناءات
and it's five acres of uninterrupted, horizontal space
و خمسة هيكتارات متصلة علي المستوي الافقي
for their administrative offices.
للمباني الاداريه
And then that, in turn, propelled us to look at
من ثم هذا يدفعنا لننظر إلى
larger-scale projects where this notion of landscape building interface
و علي نطاق أوسع مشاريع حيث مفهوم بستنة واجهات المباني
becomes a connective tissue.
تصبح نسيجا توصيليا
The new capital competition for Berlin, four years ago.
المسابقة الجديدة للعاصمة برلين ، لاربع سنوات مضت
And again we just finished the ECB --
لتونا أكملنا ال ECB
actually Coop Himmelblau in Vienna just won this project,
في الواقع هيممالبالو في فينا فاز بهذا المشروع
where the building was separated into a series of landscape elements
حيث قسم المشروع إلي عدة عناصر بستانية
that became part of a connective tissue of a park,
مما شكل عنصرا موصلا مع الحديقة
which is parallel to the river, and develops ideas of the buildings themselves
التي توازي النهر وتطور أفكار المباني في نفس الوقت
and becomes part of the connective fabric --
و تصير جزء من نسيج توصيلي
the social, cultural and the landscape, recreational fabric of the city.
النسيج الاجتماعي الثقافي والبستاني للمدينة
And the building is no longer seen as an autonomous thing,
و لا ينظر للمبني كشيء مستقل بعد ذلك
but something that's only inextricably connected
لكن شيء متصل بلا انفصام
to this city and this place at this time.
مع المدينة والمكان والزمان
And a project that was realized in Austria, the Hooper Bank,
و هذا المشروع في النمسا . بنك هوبر
which again used this idea of connecting typology,
والذي أيضا استخدم فكره رمزيه التوصيل
the traditional buildings, and morphology,
المباني التقليدية والشكل الخارجي
or the relationship of the development of land as an idea,
أو علاقة تطوير الأرض كفكرة
into a complex, which is a piece of a city where we can see part of it
الي مجمع كجزء من مدينة حيث يمكن رؤية جزء منه
is literally just this augmenting,
أنه نمو بالمعني الحرفي
this movement of the land that's a very simple idea of
هذا النوع من حركه الأرض هو فكره مبسطه من
just lifting it up and occupying it,
نوعا ما رفعها و اشغالها ليس إلا
and other parts are much more energetic and intense.
و أجزاء أخرى أكثر حيوية وانفعالا
And talk about that intensity
و يمكن التحدث عن هذه الكثافة
in terms of the collisions of the kind of events they make
بالنسبة لتصادم الاحداث إن جاز لي التعبير
that have to do with putting a series of systems together,
كما لو أنك تضع سلسلة من الانظمة مع بعدها البعض
and then where part of it is in the ground, part of it is oppositional lifts.
حيث يكون جزء منها في الأرض والجزء الاخر مرفوع في الجهة المعاكسة
One enters the building as it lifts off the ground,
حينما يدخل الواحد بينما ترفع الأرض في نفس الوقت
and it becomes part of the idea.
و تصبح جزء من الفكره نفسها
And then the skin -- the edges of this --
و من ثم الجلد --- و هذه الحواف نوعه ما
all promote the dynamic, the movement of the building
كلها تعزز الحركية ، و حركه المبني .
as a series of seismic shifts, geologic shifts. Right?
كسلسلة تحركات زلزالية، تحركات جيولوجية ، أليس كذلك
And it makes for event space and then it breaks in places
مما يشكل حيز للمناسبات و من ثم يتجزء الي عدة أماكن
that allow you to peer into the interior, and those interiors, again,
مما يسمح بالنظر الى الداخل ، و هذه التصاميم الداخلية
are promoting transparency for the workplace,
مره أخرى تعزز الشفافية ، في مكان العمل
which has been a continual interest of ours.
الذي طالما كان محل اهتمامنا
And then, again, in a more, kind of traditional setting,
و من ثم و في إطار موغل في التقليدية
this is a graduate student housing in Toronto,
هذا سكن طلبه دراسات عليا في تورونتو
and it's very much about the relationship of a building
و هو إلى حد كبير عن علاقه المبني
as it makes a connective tissue to the city.
في الوقت الذي يشكل فيه نسيج توصيلي للمدينة
The main idea was the gateway, where it breaks the site,
الفكره الاساسية كانت المدخل ، حيث تكسر الموقع
and the building occupies both the public space and the private space.
و المبني يشغل كلا من المساحه العامة و الخاصة
And it's that territory of -- it's this thing.
و لها هذه المنطقة ---كما ان لها هذا الشيء
I visited the site many times, and everybody, kind of --
لقد زرت الموقع مرات عديدة ، و أي أحد
you can see this from two kilometers away; it's an exact center of the street,
يمكن ان تري هذا من بعد كيلومترين في منتصف الطريق تماما
and the whole notion is to engage the public,
و كل الفكره ان تجذب العامة
to engage buildings as part of the public tissue of the city.
لينخرطوا في المباني كجزء من النسيج المديني
And finally, one of the most interesting projects -- it's a courthouse.
واخيرا من أكثر المشاريع المثيرة للاهتمام كان دار المحاكم \
And what I want to talk about -- this is the Supreme Court, of course --
و ما أريد التحدث عنه ---هذه المحكمة العليا ..بالطبع
and, well, I'm dealing with Michael Hogan, the Chief Justice of Oregon.
وحسنا ... أنا أتعامل مع مايكل هوجان كبير قضاة ولاية أرجون
You could not proceed without making this negotiation
لا يمكنك المواصله من غير ان تنجز هذه المفاوضة
between one's own values and the relationship
بين القيم الخاصه لواحد منا والعلاقة مع
of the character you're working with and how he understands the court,
الشخصيه التي تعمل معها و فهمه للمحكمة
because I'm showing him, of course, Corbusier at Savoy,
لاني كنت اريه بالطبع كوربوزيه ف( سافوي)
which is 1928, which is the beginning of modern architecture.
في عام 1928، حيث كانت بداية العمارة الحديثة
Well, then we get to this image.
حسنا ، من ثم انتهينا اله هذه الصورة
And this is where the project started. Because I'm going,
و من هنا ابتدأ المشروع ، لاني قلت
I'm interested in the phenomenon that's taking place in here.
أنا مهتم بالظاهرة التي نراها في هذه الصوره
And really what we're talking about is constructing reality.
و ما نتحدث عنه في الواقع هو تشييد الواقع
And I'm a character that's extremely interested
و أنا شخصيه مهتمه إلي حد بعيد
in understanding the nature of that constructed reality
في فهم طبيعه هذا الواقع
because there's no such thing as nature any more. Nature is gone.
لانه ليس هناك شيء أسمعه الطبيعه بعد اليوم ، الطبيعه ذهبت بلا عوده
Nature in the 19th-century sense, alright?
الطبيعه بمفهوم القرن التاسع عشر ، حسنا
Nature is only a cultural edifice today, right?
الطبيعه هي مفهوم يحدده المجتمع هذه الايأم ، أليس كذلك ؟
We construct it and we construct those ideas.
نحن نكونها و نحن من نكون هذه الأفكار
And then of course, this one, our governor at the moment.
و من ثم بالطبع ، هذا هو حكمنا في الوقت الراهن
And we spent some time with Conan, believe it or not,
و صدق أو لا تصدق فقد قضينا بعد الوقت مع كونان
and then that led us to, kind of, the very differences of our worlds
و هذا يقودنا إلى الاختلافات في عالمنا
from a legal and an artistic, architectural.
من الجانب القانوني ، الفني والمعماري
And it forced us to talk about notions of how we work,
مما يجبرنا علي الحديث عن مفهومنا عن طريقه عملنا
and the dynamics of that, and what other sources of the work is.
و حركية عملنا و الموارد الأخرى للعمل
And it led us to the project, the courthouse,
و في القهر أودت بنا إلى المشروع دار المحاكم
which is absolutely a part of a negotiation
الذي كان جزء من التفاوض بالتأكيد
between tradition and pieces of the traditional courthouse.
بين التقليد واجزاء من دور المحاكم التقليدية
You'll find a stair that's the same length as the Supreme Court.
ستجد درجا مشابها في طوله للمحكمة العليا
Here's a piano nobile, which is a device used in the Renaissance.
هذا بيانو نبيل الذي استخدم في عصر النهضة
The courts were made of that. The skin is this series of layers
المحكمة صنعت من هذا . الجلد هو هذه السلسلة من الطبقات
that reflect even rusticated stonework,
التي تعكس حتي أعمال الحجارة ذات الطابع الريفي
but which were embedded with fragments of the Constitution,
و التي بدورها ضمنت بين مقاطع من الدستور
which were part of the little process,
كجزء من عملية التجهيز الي حد ما
all set on a plinth that defined it from the community.
كل ذلك وضع في قاعده لتميزها من المجتمع
Thank you so much.
شكرا جزيلا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)